<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>golang on hakaselogs</title>
    <link>https://hakaselogs.me/tags/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in golang on hakaselogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© hakaselogs</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hakaselogs.me/tags/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with JSON in Go</title>
      <link>https://hakaselogs.me/2021-05-03/working-with-json-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hakaselogs.me/2021-05-03/working-with-json-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Summary: I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with JSON in various programming languages in context to data exchange/communication between applications. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll give a brief overview of the encoding/json package in Go, and point some gotchas I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered.
 Go to: Encoding | Decoding | HTTP Handler Example | Read and Write JSON to File | Streaming | Gotchas
JSON (JavaScript Object Notation), is a popular data interchange format commonly used for communication between applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enum Stringer Interface optimisation in Go</title>
      <link>https://hakaselogs.me/2021-04-08/enum-stringer-interface-optimisation-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hakaselogs.me/2021-04-08/enum-stringer-interface-optimisation-in-go/</guid>
      <description>The most idiomatic way of describing an enum type in Go is to use constants, often in conjunction with iota.
A pattern I&amp;rsquo;ve used to implement the Stringer interface for an enum type is to lookup the string representation in a slice. Consider this snippet from a project I&amp;rsquo;m working on:
// Status ... type Status uint32 // List of possible status values const ( // The operation is known, but hasn&amp;#39;t been decided yet 	Processing Status = iota // The operation will never be accepted 	Rejected // The operation was accepted 	Accepted .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Small Containers for Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://hakaselogs.me/2018-12-01/building-small-containers-for-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hakaselogs.me/2018-12-01/building-small-containers-for-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>The first step to deploying any app to Kubernetes, is to bundle the app in a container. There are several official, and community-backed container images for various languages and distros, and most of these containers can be really large, or sometimes contain overheads your app may never need/use.
Thanks to Docker, you can easily create container images in a few steps; specify a base image, add your app-specific changes, and build your container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Web App With Go, Gin and React</title>
      <link>https://hakaselogs.me/2018-04-20/building-a-web-app-with-go-gin-and-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hakaselogs.me/2018-04-20/building-a-web-app-with-go-gin-and-react/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how easy it is to build a web application with Go and the Gin framework and add authentication to it. Check out the Github repo for the code we&amp;rsquo;re going to write.
 Gin is a high-performance micro-framework that delivers a very minimalistic framework that carries with it only the most essential features, libraries, and functionalities needed to build web applications and microservices. It makes it simple to build a request handling pipeline from modular, reusable pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s What&#39;s New  In Go 1.10</title>
      <link>https://hakaselogs.me/2018-03-06/heres-whats-new-in-go-1.10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hakaselogs.me/2018-03-06/heres-whats-new-in-go-1.10/</guid>
      <description>Go 1.8 is one year old (Happy belated Birthday 🎊 🎉) Go 1.9 is already 6 months old! Go 1.10 is out ✌
 The latest Go release, v1.10 arrived six months after V1.9. This release was stated in the change-logs and the Go blog. I&amp;rsquo;m gonna share some interesting changes I&amp;rsquo;ve found in Go 1.10 with you.
New Features The Language Go 1.10 offers compiler tool chain and performance improvements, but no significant changes was made to the language&amp;rsquo;s specification.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>